Guide to the Ginger Kelly Walla Walla Balloon Stampede Scrapbooks 1972-2018
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Ginger Kelly Walla Walla Balloon Stampede Scrapbooks
1972-2018
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Kelly, Ginger (Virginia Vale)
WCMss.706
30.1 linear feet 19 flat boxes
The Ginger Kelly Walla Walla Balloon Stampede Scrapbook contains the scrapbooks of Ginger Kelly, the first female balloon pilot in Washington State. They recount the history of the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede, Kelly's involvement in national ballooning events, and other ballooning news and information
Donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by Ginger Kelly on December 17, 2018. The accession number associated with this donation is 2018-049.
The history of the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede and Ginger Kelly's ballooning career both began in September of 1972, when Chauncey Dun and his all female balloon crew flew for a demonstration at the Whitman College homecoming weekend at the request of alumni director, Jack Riehl. This event caught the attention of several Walla Walla Valley locals, including Nat Vale and Ginger Kelly of Prescott, Washington. The two began taking ballooning lessons and were certified as commercial balloon pilots in February 1974. They purchased their first balloon, Demeter, in March of that year, and flew her in the Expo '74 World's Fair in Spokane that May. The first Balloon Federation Association sanctioned balloon race in the Pacific Northwest occurred on the grounds of Walla Walla High School in May 1976. It was organized by Nat and Ginger, and their friend Bill Loyd. In 1977, Ginger placed 3rd in the first all female race during the First National Balloon Federation of America FA Balloon Races in Reno, Nevada. Ginger Kelly continued to be involved in ballooning events across the Pacific Northwest, and in 1994 she was named the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede volunteer of the year. In 1999 she served as the Honorary Balloonmeister for the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede, and in 2004 she was presented with a Balloon Federation of America award for outstanding service to the history of ballooning. The Walla Walla Balloon Stampede has continued to hold a valued position as an annual community and regional event, and in 1990 the site moved from Walla Walla High School to its current location at Howard Tietan Park.
The Ginger Kelly Walla Walla Balloon Stampede Scrapbook contains the scrapbooks of Ginger Kelly, the first female balloon pilot in Washington State. The collection, which dates from 1972 to 2018, consists of scrapbooks, evidencing how the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede began, how it progressed, the people associated with the stampede, and national balloon news. It provides a broad look at ballooning history and culture, as well as the impact the Walla Walla Balloon Stampede has had on the local community.
Walla Walla (Wash.)
Ballooning
- Scrapbook, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1974 (Box 1, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 1975 (Box 1, Object 3)
- Scrapbook, 1976 (Box 2, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1977 (Box 2, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Object 3)
- Scrapbook, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 1987 (Box 3, Object 3)
- Scrapbook, 1988 (Box 4, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1989 (Box 4, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 1990 (Box 4, Object 3)
- Scrapbook, 1991 (Box 5, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1992 (Box 5, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 1993 (Box 5, Object 3)
- Scrapbook, 1994 (Box 6, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 1995 (Box 6, Object 3, Box 7, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1996 (Box 7, Object 2-3)
- Scrapbook, 1997 (Box 8, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 1998 (Box 8, Object 3, Box 9, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 1999 (Box 9, Object 2-3)
- Scrapbook, 2000 (Box 10, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 2001 (Box 10, Object 3-4)
- Scrapbook, 2002 (Box 11, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 2003 (Box 11, Object 3, Box 12, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 2004 (Box 12, Object 2-3)
- Scapbook, 2005 (Box 13, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 2006 (Box 13, Object 3, Box 14, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 2007 (Box 14, Object 2-3)
- Scrapbook, 2008 (Box 15, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 2009 (Box 15, Object 3-4)
- Scrapbook, 2010 (Box 16, Object 1-2)
- Scrapbook, 2011 (Box 16, Object 3, Box 17, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 2012 (Box 17, Object 2-3)
- Scrapbook, 2013 (Box 18, Object 3-4)
- Scrapbook, 2014 (Box 18, Object 1)
- Scrapbook, 2015 (Box 18, Object 2)
- Scrapbook, 2016-2018 (Box 19, Object 1)